Hello guys, I am going to
review my youtube1 multi cap fund and
tell you about it. So the video will be in full detail.
I will show you the fundamental analysis in an excel sheet
and
in the conclusion at the end, I will also tell you whether you should
invest in it or not
and if you
should invest in it, then for how many years should you do it. So, do
subscribe to my channel,
I will bring this video. So
let's start. First of all, let me
tell you that if you look at the SEBI guidelines in the multi-cap related category
funds, then
they have
said that your minimum allocation up
to 25% should be in the small cap category, up to
25% should be in the mid-cap category
and up to 25% should be in the landscape
category, so your total weight should be
75% and the remaining 25%, which means the
portfolio that is formed, you can allocate it in another category, that is,
in your category, so you can allocate it in
whichever category you want, you
can do it in large cap as well as mid-cap.  In small cap or small
cap, it totally depends on the fund
managers, so there are some
restrictions here, so
I am going to discuss and tell you about that in
detail, as you
can see on my screen here,
if you see its launch date, it is in 11th of 2017, that is, if you look at
this particular fund, it has been
7.4 years since its launch, so if you look at
its category return,
in 7.4 years it has a return of up to 17.55%,
but if you look at the return of this fund,
in 7.4 years it has a return of up to 20.8%,
so you can see that it is giving its category
beating return, that is, if you
see, it has beaten it by 3%, which is a
very good margin, if you
look continuously for 7.4 years, if suppose
you wanted to invest in this particular fund, then if you had done it,
you would have done it
continuously for 5 years.  If it had
happened then the amount deposited by you would have been
0000 and 0000 would have been converted
into ₹ 33000, you can also see
that the money of 5 years is getting more than double, so
how great returns it is giving
and how much
you would be seeing the power of investment here, if suppose
instead of investing in this fund
you would have invested in gold
for 5 years, then continuously the amount
deposited would have been converted into ₹ 0000 and would have become
₹ 660000 after 5 years in ₹ 727, if suppose you had invested in FD then your amount deposited 0000 would have been converted into ₹ 660000
in 727, so you can see that the
power of investment here means that you have
only ₹ 1 more in FD and it is
giving a little better return than gold and this which
you have  There is a fund in which you can see that the
money has more than doubled, so
you can immediately see
why it is important to invest. Now if we
talk about return versus category, then it will be above
average return. Definitely, it is
category beating return. See,
I have told you in every video that
category beating return is very important,
it is not how much return a
particular fund is giving you. You should not look at this.
Category beating return is very important. The
reason is that if you have
invested in such a small cap fund
and if the category beating return is
giving you up to 30% return, you will say that it is
giving a very good return, but
you are also facing the wallet here, so
facing the wallet, if the category i.e. its
index fund is giving you less
return, then what is the benefit, so that is
why it becomes a little important to have category beating return. So
here, if the category beating
return is very good, that too above, that means
this return is from the category.  It is more than three times 3 per.
Now if we talk about risk versus category here, then
how is the average as per the risk category, here
we will talk about risk and return ratio, so
if you look at its beta, what is beta basically, that is
your wallet with respect
to its benchmark, so
if you look here, its beta is 1.07
and if we look at the category, it is 0.9, so you
can see that here you have taken a little more risk
and very much, I am telling you, it is
necessary to be below one, that
here it is above one, it is 1.07, so here
definitely a lot of risk will remain
and you will get to see a strong wallet,
then here you are getting a
massive return of up to 20 per, that too
in 7.4 years, now if we talk about standard deviation here, then if we
compare the standard deviation here, then basically it is
how much plus is it from your average return, how much can be made from
it,
you know that range.  It is said that yes,
within this range you have chances of getting returns,
so here the risk
of this fund is 16.99 and the category here is
14.49, so if we see, the lower the
better, the more the category means
you will get a lot more returns here,
so there is definitely a higher
risk here, that is why you are getting higher returns in this, so there is nothing
surprising here,
but here you could have taken a little less
risk, so here I will
give a little negative feedback, in terms of risk, the
risk is becoming a little higher, that is, it is becoming
in this particular fund, if you
want to invest in it, then
you can start the minimum SIP from ₹00, so
even for students, nowadays students
are also investing from ₹00, so this is very
good, if you want to do a lump sum in it, then you
can start the lump sum from ₹000, which is
very good, if we talk about the lock-in period, then there is no
lock-in period in this, once
you have made this investment, you can  I
exited from it, which is a very
good thing. Talking about AM size, the
full form of AM is Asset Under
Management. So if we look at it, then
basically you get to know
how much money is invested in this particular fund. So, from this
you get to know that if
your M size is less, then you think that if it is less, then
most people are not trusting it, there is
some problem in it, that is why not many people are
investing and not
much is invested in it, then you come to
know this from this and if it is more than M, then the
fund manager faces management
problems. So, like the problem in management, for example, suppose
you might have seen that people
stop SIPs, stop LSAMs, then
what is the problem, this is the reason why the
problem arises. So, the
closer your AVM size is to the middle, the
better it is. If it is more, there is
not much problem, but if it is less, then there is a
big problem. So, talking about M size here,
this fund is 7.4 years old
and it has approximately
4686  There is an M size of up to crores. I was
telling you in every video that if your
fund is more than 10 years old and less than 15 years old,
then your M size should be between Rs 00 crore to Rs 0000
crore, which is
considered to be the best, so
if you look here, it is 4686, that too
in 7-7.4 years, which means it is close to 5000, so if you look at it, nothing is
too bad, nothing is too
less, nothing is too much, which means it is not too big, so if you
look at it, it is absolutely
good, in terms of M size, I will
not give any positive or negative feedback here, it is
absolutely good, talking about expenses,
see, you have to use your brain, the one who
uses your brain is your fund manager,
so the fund manager is investing with your brain and getting
you returns,
so today he has to pay some management fee, so if this
management fee is
below 1, then it is quite good
because I am telling you that at 1, in the long term, there is a
difference of lakhs of crores,
so here it is at 0.41, which is absolutely good and what
I have said  The criteria have been set, if it is
below 0.7 then it is considered good, so
here 0.41 is considered very good,
you can consider it and
I will give you positive feedback about it.
Talking about tax information,
if you suppose you exit before one year, then you have booked
20% profit, then you will have to pay
tax up to 20% on the profit and
if you exit after one year then you will have to pay
tax of 12.5% ​​on the profit,
so you will have to pay this only if you
come to the Indian Income Tax Department,
suppose you exit one year before then
you will have to pay an exit load of 1%
and suppose you
exit after one year then you do not need to pay any exit load.
Now the most important thing is
capital, as I told you, it is
necessary to have 25% in all, so here we
can see that there is an allocation of up to 25.1% in mid cap and 10%
in small cap.  There
is allocation up to 27.6, there is allocation of 44.9 in large cap
and there is allocation up to 2.3 in depth and others, so
as you can see
that it means they have taken minimum 25 and 27 in mid cap and small
cap, which means
they have taken risk up to 52, the rest which is
at 48, their allocation is mostly in large cap and
depth, which is absolutely reasonable
because see, if there is a little more allocation in large cap
then you will be able to run a little safe,
at 50, anyway they have already taken
risk by taking small cap and mid cap,
so here if you can see that that is why this
return was given to you from 18 to 20
because it is a
little more risky than large cap, sorry, it is a
little less risky than mid cap, so in
between large cap and mid cap, if you want to
take risk and want returns in the range of 18 to 20, then
you should choose multi cap.  One
should go towards such a fund,
so in the case of market capital,
I cannot say anything here that look, there
is a limitation here, SEBI has set guidelines,
so there is no problem in it,
they have tried to take less risk as much as possible,
but the risk could have been taken less,
see, you have seen more vaat, that is,
if you look at other multi-cap, you will not see much vaat in them,
but here you have
seen more, so definitely
more risk can be taken here,
but they have taken more risk, so they will have to
revise it a little, so let's
talk about sector allocation, there
is 20.75 percent in financial services,
15.4 percent in consumer cyclical,
1.29 percent in industrials,
11.5 percent in technology sector,
10.43 percent in basic materials,
9.27 percent in consumer defensive,
8.15 percent in energy sector,
health care  I have a calculation of 4.54,
communication services have a calculation of 1.15,
real estate has a
calculation of 0.53. So, if we look at it, it is
perfect in terms of diversification. The
top five sectors are financial services,
consumer cyclical, after that you have
industrials, then technology and basic
materials. These five sectors
give good performance, this particular fund will
give you good performance. So,
in these five sectors, they are well
diversified, so I will give
positive feedback on the diversification parameter here. There will be
positive feedback on the sector allocation parameter.
Talking about the fund manager, there are
two fund managers here. One is Manish Lodha,
he has an experience of 3.82 years. The second is
Fatima Pacha, her experience is four
years. So, see, a fund manager should have
more experience here,
even if there is not much experience here, but there is a
decent experience. You
can track the returns with this, that is, look at
these two funds right now.  These are the managers.
What kind of returns have they delivered in the last four years?
In which funds have they worked? And
what is their strategy? You
can find out this beforehand and invest accordingly.
So this will be positive feedback. If they had
experience of half a year or a year, you wouldn't have been able to find out. There would have been a
problem. So you
can do research about them here. This will
definitely be positive feedback. Now,
talking about the rating, the rating here will be four out of
five. Look, here, four out of five is
one thing. They have given massive returns.
I am telling you,
if you look at the multicap category, you will
get an all-time return of 18 or 19 percent,
but they have given returns up to 21 percent.
Definitely, according to that,
they have taken a little more risk.
If you look at its beta, then beta
more than one means it is dangerous. So, it
is 1.07. So, definitely, you will have to face this dangerous wallet
if you invest in this fund.  In
comparison to other
multicap categories, if you
look at other multicaps, you can look at those in which you can
take a little less risk and you may
get a little less return, so
you can look at that. But if you
want to try to take a little more risk, that
means your multicap is
in between large cap and mid cap in terms of risk. Mid cap is more risky than large cap,
so it is in between large cap and mid
cap. So,
suppose you get an all-time return of 15 to 16 per cent in large cap, then
in multi cap
you get a return of 18 to 20 per cent.
In mid cap you get a return of 20 to 24 or 25 per cent.
In small cap
you get a return of 20 to 30 or 35 or even 40
because that is very
risky, so you will see more volatility in that. So
here, if you
want to adjust the return a little by taking a little risk from mid cap, that means you can go for large  If you
want to get a little more return than cap and also
want to adjust the risk a little, then
you can go towards multi-cap. After that,
before that, you can also do research on other multi-caps. So, if you
look at this, it is a little risky. Definitely,
here you can see that the sand
deviation and your beta are a little more
risky, but you
can definitely invest in this, the returns are very
good, but your time frame should be a minimum of 7 years
because here a
little more risk is being taken, so 7 years is
your minimum time frame, so definitely
you can
invest in this particular mutual fund. Do not invest all the money
in this particular mutual fund, do your own
research and
invest by diversifying yourself. There
is detail about the fund managers here, that means you
can see their experience,
research about them, research in which stocks they
invested the money. After that,
here I have told you about the sexual allocation and
market capital
in detail, so you should know all these things and
then invest.  Only then will you
feel a little confident, so
please subscribe to my channel, I keep
bringing such videos, thank you.